ACT ONE
This is about my broken heart
You think through life a bit differently
when you are told how this would all end
That's the shock that people live
their whole lives re-directing
But my time is fixed to the signs
my doctors use
to understand my heartbeat
My heartbeat is proving fatal
Anyone should know that
living in constant shock
is not really shocking any longer
It becomes something else entirely
My heartbeat was not always erratic
At least I can't believe it
was always like this
It never got so bad that
I would lose sensation
in my chest and all sense of time
It was pretty bad when it first started
I mean
I think it is
a little funny
I was singing the song about the horses
You must remember it
it is a very famous Cantonese melody
The song itself is about the potency
of strength and
courage of these horses
They escape the grasp of those that want
claim to the land
and if it wasn't the land
it would be a claim to their bodies
& they were forced to
always keep moving
Prevailing
and so on
You must remember this
song since it is very famous
If I sing it for you,
you will recognize it
When it gets translated
from Cantonese into English,
it becomes a love song
This is the reason why Sin Ya asked
me to perform this song at her wedding
There's a subliminal quality to it
When the audience heard
the beginning notes, they
clinked their glasses
and clapped their hands
The simple joy in recognition
When I entered the first chorus, I started
to feel my chest tighten and lost focus
I no longer could control how I was hitting
my notes and my vision became blurry
In that moment I also
realized that the English
version of the song got
rid of the horses completely
There was no longer any trace of
them in the words coming from my mouth
I was taking part
in a violence
towards these horses
And like a wave that
reaches it's crest
the pressure in my chest
bloomed beyond my control
My body went from heat to
ice, I shrank into my dress and I
could feel the rattle in my heart
sending blood up to my ears
I couldn't even hear myself singing
Later my cousin told me
I sang the entire song fine
It was only afterwards that
I grew pale and collapsed
Fainting after singing a
love song at a wedding
How special
An unforgettable song for
an unforgettable wedding
Sin Ya and her partner
are together to this day
Did that love song keep
them together for this long?
I would like to think so
Prevailing and so on
I was diagnosed with arrhythmia
shortly after that incident
If you are willing to believe it
I've been monitoring my heartbeat since
It's been two decades now
If you didn't know the precariousness
of my condition you might
assume this type of surveillance
of my health is overkill
The data of my heart
alone is well over 6 terabytes
I look for signs of turbulence over
the course of weeks, months, years
I keep a journal and try to think of even
the smallest things that happen each day
To try to piece together
the root of my condition
This is about my broken heart
THE END